大家好，让我们开始下一堂课。
All right everyone let's get started with the next lecture.
今天我们将解决元编程的主题，
So, today we're gonna tackle the topic of meta programming,
这个标题有点奇怪。
and this title is a little weird.
我们并没有完全清楚元编程的含义。
It's not entirely clear what we mean by meta programming.
我们在命名这个讲座时想不出更好的名字，
We couldn't really come up with a better name for this lecture
因为这个讲座是关于
because this lecture is about the processes
你在使用软件时所进行的工作周围的过程，
that surround the work that you do when working with software.
不一定是编程本身，而是关于这个过程的内容。
It is not about programming itself necessarily but about the process.
这可能涉及到如何构建你的系统、如何进行测试、
This can be things like how your system is built, how it's tested,
如何添加软件依赖等等，
how you add dependencies to your software,
这些内容在构建较大的软件时
that sort of stuff that becomes really relevant
变得非常重要，
when you build larger pieces of software,
但它们本身并不是编程。
but they're not really programming in and of themselves.
所以，我们这堂课首先要讨论的是构建系统的概念。
So, the first thing we're going to talk about in this lecture is the notion of build systems.
有多少人使用过构建系统或知道它是什么？好的，
So, how many of you have used a build system before or know what it is? Okay,
大约有一半的人。
so about 1/2 of you.
那么对于其余的人来说，构建系统的核心思想是，你正在编写一篇论文、
So, for the rest of you, the central idea behind a build system is that you're writing a paper,
编写软件、或者在学习某个课程，无论是哪种情况，
you're writing software, you're working on a class, whatever it might be,
你都有一堆命令，你可能把它们写在你的 shell 历史记录中，
and you have a bunch of commands that you like either written down in your shell history
或者在某个文档中记下来，
or you wrote them down in a document somewhere
你知道如果想要完成特定的任务，必须运行这些命令序列。
that you know you have to run if you want to do a particular thing.
例如，有一系列的命令需要按顺序运行，
So, for example, there are a sequence of commands
以便构建你的论文或论文的 PDF 版本，
so you need to run in order to build your paper or build your thesis
或者只是运行当前课程的测试。
or just to run the tests for whatever class you're currently in,
构建系统的想法是，你想把这些规则编码成一个工具，
and a build system sort of idea is that you want to encode these rules for what commands
这个工具可以为你完成这些任务。
to run in order to build particular targets into a tool that can do it for you.
特别是，你要教这个工具了解
And in particular, you're going to teach this tool about the dependencies
构建不同工件之间的依赖关系。
between those different artifacts that you might build.
有许多不同类型的这种工具，
There are a lot of different types of tools of this kind,
许多是针对特定目的、特定语言构建的。
and many of them are built for particular purposes, particularly languages.
有些是用于构建论文，
Some of them are built for building papers,
有些是用于构建软件，
some of them are built for building software,
有些是用于特定的编程语言，比如 Java 或某些其他的语言。
some of them are built for particularly programming languages like Java or some.
有些工具甚至内置了构建工具，
Some tools even have built-in tools for builds.
例如 NPM，如果你做过 Node.js 开发，
So, NPM, for example, you might be aware if you've done Node.js development,
可能就知道它具有跟踪依赖项
has a bunch of built-in tools for doing tracking of dependencies and building them
和构建依赖项的内置工具。
and building all of the dependent stuff of your software.
但更一般地说，这些被称为构建系统，
But more generally, these are known as build systems,
在它们的核心中，它们都有一些共同的功能。
and at their core, they all function in a very similar way.
它们有许多目标，
And that is, you have a number of targets.
这些目标是你想要构建的东西，
These are the things that you want to build.
比如 paper.pdf，
These are things like paper dot PDF,
但它们也可以是更抽象的东西，比如运行测试套件或构建程序的二进制文件。
but they can also be more abstract things like run the test suite or build the binary for this program.
然后，你有一堆依赖项，
Then you have a bunch of dependencies,
依赖项是需要构建的东西，以便构建这个目标
and dependencies are things that need to be built in order for this thing to be built.
然后你有一些规则，
And then you have rules that define how do you go from
规定如何从完整的依赖项列表中得到目标文件。
a complete list of dependencies to the given target.
举个例子，如果要构建我的paper.pdf，
So, an example of this might be, in order to build my paper.pdf,
我需要一些绘图图像，
I need a bunch of like plot images.
它们将被嵌入到论文中，
They're gonna go into the paper,
因此需要构建它们。
so they need to be built.
但是一旦它们被构建，如何使用这些文件来构建论文呢？
But then once they have been built, how do I construct the paper given those files?
这就是规则的作用。
So that is what a rule is.
它是一系列命令，你需要运行它们才能完成从一个文件到另一个文件的转换。
It's a sequence of command, so you run to get from one to the other.
如何编码这些规则因不同的工具而异。
How you encode these rules differs between different tools.
在这门课程中，我们将关注一种叫做make的工具。
In this particular class, we're gonna focus on a tool called make.
make是一种几乎可以在今天登录的任何系统上找到的工具。
Make is a tool that you will find on almost any system that you log in today.
比如，它会在Mac OS上，基本上所有的Linux和BSD系统上找到，
Like, it'll be on Mac OS, it'll be on basically every Linux and BSD system,
而且你也可以很容易地在Windows上获取它。
and you can pretty easily get it on Windows.
它不适用于非常复杂的软件，
It's not great for very complex software,
但对于任何简单到中等复杂度的东西都可以很好地工作。
but it works really well for anything that's sort of simple to medium complexity.
当你在命令行上运行make命令时，
Now, when you run make to make user command, you can run on the command line,
如果目录为空
and when you type make and this is an empty directory,
并且没有指定目标并且找不到makefile，它就会停止。
if I type make, it just has no target specified and no make file found, stop.
它会告诉你已经停止运行，
And so it helpfully tells you that it stopped running,
但也会告诉你找不到makefile。
but also tells you that no make file was found.
make将在当前目录中查找一个名为Makefile的文件，
Make will look for a file literally called Makefile in the current directory,
这就是你编码这些目标、依赖项和规则的地方。
and that is where you encode these targets, dependencies,  and rules.
所以，让我们试着写一个makefile吧。
So, let's try to write one.
假设我正在写这篇假想的论文，
Let's imagine that I'm writing this hypothetical paper,
所以我要创建一个Makefile，
and so I'm gonna make a Makefile,
在这个Makefile中，我将声明我的paper.pdf
and then in this Makefile, I'm going to say that my paper.pdf,
是由paper.tex、
the hands-on, that's what the colon here indicates.
plotdata.png
paper.tex was going to be a little attack file,
这两个文件构建而来，
and plot-data.png,
构建这个文件的命令是使用PDF latex命令。
and the command in order to build this is going to be pdflatex paper.tex.
对于那些不熟悉这种构建文档的方式的人来说，
So, for those of you who are not familiar with this particular way of building documents,
TeX是一种非常方便的文档编程语言。
the tex is a really handy programming language for documents.
它是一种非常难看的语言，
It's a really ugly language,
使用起来很麻烦，
and it's a pain to work with,
但它可以产生很好的文档。
but it produces pretty nice documents.
而将TeX文件转换成PDF的工具就是PDF latex。
And the tool you use to go from a tech file to PDF is pdf latex.
这里我需要用到一个plot数据的PNG文件，
And here, I'm saying that I also depend on this plot-data.png
这个文件将会被包含在我的文档中。
that's gonna be included in my document.
我想要表达的是，如果这两个依赖关系中的任意一个发生了变化，
And what I'm really saying here is if either of those two dependencies change,
我希望生成paper PDF文件。
I want you to build paper.pdf.
这两个文件都需要存在，如果它们发生了变化，我希望重新生成。
They both need to be present,  and should they ever change, I wanted to rebuild it.
但我并没有告诉它如何生成这个plot数据的PNG文件，
But I haven't really told it how to generate this plot-data.png,
因此我可能还需要一个规则。
so I might want a rule for that as well.
因此，我在这里定义了另一个目标，
So, I'm gonna define another target here,
它的样子是这样的：plot - %，
and it's gonna look like this: plot - % ,and % means make,
然后%代表任意字符串，
and make is any string,
可以理解为通配符模式。
sort of a wildcard pattern.
但是，很酷的一点是，当你在依赖关系中重复这个模式时，
But the cool thing is as you go and repeat this pattern in the dependencies,
我可以说，plot - %.png将依赖于%.data或debt，
so I can say that plot - %.png is going to depend on %.data or debt,
这是一种常见的数据文件后缀。
that is a common sort of suffix for data files.
它还将依赖于一些脚本，这个脚本将实际为我绘制这个图形，
And it's also going to depend on some script that's gonna actually plot this for me,
而从一个文件格式到另一个文件格式的规则可以是多行的，
and the rules for to go from one to the other, these can be multiple lines,
但在我这个特定的例子中，只有一行。
but in my particular case, they're just one line.
我会在接下来的时候解释这是什么意思。
I'm gonna explain what this is in a little second.
好的，所以在这里，我们要说的是，
Alright,  so here we're gonna say that in order to
为了从通配符点点文件（与目标中的通配符匹配）
go from a wildcard dot dot file that matches the wildcard in the target
和plot.py文件转换，运行python文件，并且使用-i参数，
and a plot.py file, run the python file with - i
这类似于我们在python文件中标记输入的方式。
which is going to be like the way we take the mark what the input is in our python file.
稍后我会向您展示它。
I'll show it to you later.
$*是一个为您定义的特殊变量，
$* is a special variable that is defined for you
可以匹配任何百分号。
and make file rules that matches whatever the percentile was.
因此，如果我做plot/.foo.png，那么它将查找foo.dat，
So, if I do plot/.foo.png, then it's going to look for foo.dat
它的星号可以扩展为foo。
and it $* can expand to foo.
所以，这将产生与我们在此处匹配的文件名相同的文件名，
So, this will produce the same file name as the one we matched here
而$@是一个特殊变量，表示目标的名称，对吧？
and $@ as a special variable that means the name of the target, right?
所以，输出文件，
So, the output file,
希望plotter py会获取这里的任何数据，
and hopefully what plot.py will do
它将以某种方式生成PNG文件，
is that it will take whatever the data is here, it will produce a PNG somehow,
并将其写入由dollar all指示的文件中，对吧？
and it will write it into the file indicated by the $@, right?
现在我们有了一个make文件。
So now we have a make file.
让我们看看如果这个目录中唯一的文件是make文件，而我们运行make会发生什么。
Let's see what happens if the only file in this directory is the make file,  and we run make.
它会说："no rule to make target paper.tex needed by paper.pdf，stop。"
One says no rule to make target paper.tex needed by paper.pdf, stop.
所以，它在这里所表达的是，首先，它查看了我们文件的第一条规则，也就是第一个目标，
So, what it's saying here is, first of all, it looked at the first rule of our file, the first target,
当你没有给make任何参数时，它会尝试构建第一个目标。
and when you give make no arguments, it tries to build whatever the first target is.
这被称为默认目标。
This is known as the default goal.
因此，在这种情况下，它试图为我们有用地构建paper.pdf文件，
So, in this case, it tried to helpfully build paper.pdf for us,
然后查找它的依赖关系，
and then it looked up the dependencies,
它说：“为了构建paper.pdf，我需要paper.tex
and it said, well, in order to build paper.pdf, I need paper.tex,
和这个PNG文件。
and I need this PNG file.
我找不到paper.tex的文件，
And I can't find paper.tex
也没有生成paper.tex的规则，
and I don't have a rule for generating paper.tex,
因此我要退出。
and therefore I'm gonna exit.
我无能为力了。
This isn't nothing more I can do.
所以，让我们尝试在这里创建一些文件。
So, let's try to make some files here.
我们可以创建一个空的paper.X文件，然后输入make命令。
Let's just make like an empty paper.tex and then type make.
现在它会显示“paper to PDF”需要plot-data.PNG文件，但是没有相关规则。
So now it says no rule to make target plot-data.png needed by paper to PDF, right?
现在它知道它有一个依赖项，
So now it knows that it has one dependency,
但它不知道如何获取另一个依赖项。
but it doesn't know how to get the other one.
它知道有一个与之匹配的目标，
It knows it as a target that matches,
但实际上找不到依赖项，
but it can't actually find its dependencies,
所以它最终什么都没有做。
and so it ends up doing nothing at all.
它仍然需要我们为PNG的输入生成这个PNG文件。
It still needs us to generate this PNG for the input for the PNG.
因此，让我们实际上在这些文件中添加一些有用的内容。
So, let's actually put some useful stuff into these files.
幸运的是，我之前从plot.da.py中获得了一个，
Let's say that luckily I have one from earlier plot.py to here,
所以很好。
so let's so good.
那么，这个文本文件是文本的样子。
Well, this text file is what text looks like.
它不是很漂亮，
It's not very pretty,
但是我定义了一个空文档。
but see, I'm defining an empty document.
我将包含图形，这是包含图像文件的方式。
I'm going to include graphics, which is the way you include an image file.
我将包含plot-data.PNG，
I'm going to include plot-data.png,
这当然是为什么我们希望paper.PDF的依赖项是PNG文件。
and this is of course why we want a dependency of paper.pdf to be the PNG file.
plot.py也不是很有趣。
plot.py is also not very interesting.
它只是导入了一堆库。
It just imports a bunch libraries.
它解析了-i和-o参数。
It parses the - i and - o arguments.
它从-i参数中加载数据。
It loads data from the -i argument.
它使用了一个称为matplotlib的库，这对于快速绘制数据非常方便。
It uses library called matplotlib, which is very handy for just quickly plotting data.
它将数据的第一列绘制为X轴，第二列绘制为Y轴。
And it's going to plot the first column of the data as X's and the second column of the data as Y's.
因此，我们只需要一个每行都有两列X和Y的数据文件，
So, we're just going to have a data file that's two columns, X and Y on every line,
然后将其保存为给定的-oh值的图像。
and then it saves that as a figure into whatever the given - o values.
因此，我们需要一个命名为data.dat的数据文件，因为我们需要plot-data.png，
So we need a data file that's going to be data.dat because we want plot-data.png,
而我们的规则指定了从该模式到点文件的方式，
and our rules said that the way you go from that pattern to
即按照plot之后的内容来确定点文件的名称。
the .file, the . that file is just by whatever follows plot.
因此，如果我们需要plot-data，则我们需要data.dat文件。
So if we want plot-data, then we want data.dat
然后这个文件，我们只是要把它放入一些线性坐标，因为为什么不呢？
And then this file, we're just gonna put in some linear coordinates because why not?
那不是线性的。好的。
That's not linear.  All right.
现在，如果我们要做什么，嗯，好的，
And now, what happens if we're gonna make, well, mmm, okay,
那么刚刚发生了什么？嗯，make首先用正确的文件运行plot.py生成PNG文件，
so what just happened? Well, make first ran plot.py with the correct files to generate the PNG file,
然后它运行pdf latex paper.tex，
and then it ran pdf latex paper.tex,
我们下面看到的所有内容都是该工具的输出。
and all the stuff we see below is the output from that tool.
如果你想的话，我们可以消除这个工具的输出，
If you wanted to, we silence the effort from this tool,
这样我们就不必让它干扰我们的所有输出，
so we don't have to like have it mess with all our output,
但是通常情况下，你会注意到它运行了两个命令，
but in general, you notice that it ran the two commands, then it wrote the random,
然后以正确的顺序写入了随机值。
perhaps unsurprisingly, in the right order.
如果我们现在在当前目录下运行ls，我们会发现我们有一堆文件
And if we now do ls in the current directory, we see that we have a bunch of files
是由pdf latex生成的，
that were generated by pdf latex,
但特别的是，我们有生成的PNG文件
but in particular, we have the PNG file which was generated,
和paper.pdf。
and we have the paper.pdf.
如果我们打开paper.pdf文件，我们会看到它有一个图像，其中有一条直线，
And if we open the paper.pdf file, we see that it has one image which has the straight line,
也许本身并不是一个非常令人惊讶或有趣的结果，
perhaps in and of itself not a very surprising or interesting result,
但这真的非常方便，我可以做一些像如果我再次输入make，make只是说paper.pdf是最新的。
but where this gets really handy is I can do things like if I type make again, make just says paper.pdf is up to date.
它不做任何工作。
It does no work.
每当你运行make时，它尝试以最小的工作量来产生你要求的任何东西。
Whenever you run make, it tries to do the minimal amount of work in order to produce whatever you ask it to produce.
在这种情况下，没有任何依赖项发生变化，
In this case, none of the dependencies have changed,
因此没有重建paper或重建图。
so there's no reason to rebuild the paper or to rebuild the plot.
现在假设我要编辑paper.tex，
If I now let's say I'm gonna edit paper.tex,
我要在这里添加hello，现在做make，
I'm gonna add hello here and now make,
然后如果我们向上滚动，我们会看到它没有再次运行plot.py，因为我不需要它。
then if we scroll up, we'll see it didn't run plot.py again because I didn't need to.
没有依赖项发生变化，
None of the dependencies changed,
但它确实再次运行了pdf latex。
but it did run pdf latex again.
如果我们打开paper，分析hello在那里。
And indeed, if we open the paper, analysis hello over there.
另一方面，如果我改变数据文件，然后把这个点改为每小时8美元，
On the other hand, if I were to change say the data file and make this point 8 an hour and make,
然后再做，那么现在它会重新绘制图形，因为数据发生了改变，
then now it plots again because the data changed,
并且它会重新生成PDF，因为图形发生了改变。
and it regenerates the PDF because the plot changed.
确实，这篇论文的结果是我们预期的。
And indeed, the paper turns out the way we expected it to.
所以这并不是说这个特定的管道非常有趣，因为它不是。
So that's not to say that this particular pipeline is very interesting because it's not.
它只对非常非常简单的目标和规则有效。
It's only true very, very straightforward targets and rules.
但是当你开始构建更大的软件或可能存在依赖关系时，
But this can come in really handy
这会非常有用。
when you start building larger pieces of software or there might be dependencies.
你甚至可以想象，如果你在写论文，
You might even imagine that if you're writing a paper,
你的一个目标可能是首先生成这个数据文件，对吧？
one of your targets might be producing this data file in the first place, right?
因此，其中一个makefile目标可能是运行我的实验，对吧？
So one of the makefile targets might be run my experiment, right?
运行我的基准测试并将输出的数据点放入此文件中，
Run my benchmark and stick the data points that come out into this file
然后绘制结果，
and then plot the results
一直到最终论文完成。
and then and then and then and then all the way until you end up with a final paper.
这样做的好处是，首先你不必记住运行所有命令的方式，
And what's nice about this is, first of all, you don't have to remember all the commands to run.
也不必在任何地方写下来，
You don't have to write them down anywhere,
工具会处理最少量的工作量。
but also the tool takes care of doing the minimal amount of work needed.
通常情况下，你会发现有些事情也太麻烦了。
Often you'll find things like they'll be too.
例如，还有子命令需要执行，如 make tests，
There'll be sub-commands to make, like make tests, right?
它会编译整个软件并运行测试。
Which is going to compile your entire piece of software and also run the tests.
还可能有像 make release 这样的东西，
There might be things like make release,
它会打开优化并创建一个 tarball
which builds it with optimizations turned on
并将其上传到某个地方。
and creates a tarball and uploads that somewhere, right?
因此，它会为你完成整个流程。
So it's gonna do the whole pipeline for you.
这样做的目的是减少构建过程中你必须做的工作量。
The idea is to reduce the effort that you have to do as any part of your build process.
现在我们看到了一个非常简单的依赖示例，对吧？
Now what we saw here was a very straightforward example of dependencies, right?
我们看到了你可以将文件声明为依赖项，
So we saw here that you could declare files as dependencies,
但你也可以声明传递依赖项。
but you can also declare sort of transitive dependencies.
当你在更大的软件领域中处理依赖项时，
I depend on this thing which is generate by the other targer
通常会发现你的系统最终会有许多不同类型的依赖项。
Very often when you work with dependencies in the larger area of software,
其中一些是
you'll find that your system ends up having many different types of dependencies.
像我们在这里看到的文件，
Some of these are files like we saw here,
有些是程序，
some of them are programs, like this
比如这个程序隐含依赖于 Python 在我的机器上安装。
sort of implicitly depends on Python being installed on my machine.
有些可能是库，
Some of it might be libraries,
比如你可能依赖于像 matplotlib 这样的东西，我们在这里也依赖于它。
like you might depend on something like matplotlib, which we depend on here.
有些可能是系统库，如 OpenSSL
Some of them might be system libraries like OpenSSL
或 OpenSSH 或低级密码库，
or OpenSSH or like low-level crypto libraries,
你不一定要声明所有这些依赖项。
and you don't necessarily declare all of them.
通常情况下，
what you find it that for most places where you have dependences
有一些工具可以帮助你管理这些依赖项。
there are tools for managing denpendences for you
而且，这些你可能依赖的系统通常存储在所谓的存储库中。
And very often, these systems you might depend on are stored in what are known as repositories.
存储库只是一组通常相关的事物，你可以安装它们。
So a repository is just a collection of things usually related that you can install.
这基本上就是存储库的全部内容，
That's basically all a repository is,
你可能已经熟悉其中的一些，对吧？
and you might be familiar with some of them already, right?
存储库的一些示例包括 PyPI，
So some examples of repositories are PyPI,
这是一个众所周知的 Python 包存储库，RubyGems，
which is a well-known repository for Python packages, RubyGems,
这是 Ruby 的类似存储库，crates.io 是 Rust 的存储库，NPM 是 Node.js 的存储库，
which is similar for Ruby, crates.io for Rust, NPM for Node.js,
但其他东西也有存储库，对吧？
but other things have repositories too, right?
例如，有加密密钥的存储库，如 Keybase，
Like there are repositories for cryptographic keys like Keybase,
有系统安装包的存储库，
there are repositories for system-installed packages
如果你在 Ubuntu 或 Debian 中使用 apt 工具，
like if you ever use the apt tool in Ubuntu or in Debian,
则正在与一个包存储库交互，
you are interacting with a package repository
人们上传他们编写的程序和库，
where people who have written programs and libraries upload them
以便你可以安装它们。
so that you can then install them.
同样地，你可能会有完全开放的仓库，
Similarly, you might have repositories that are entirely open,
比如说 Ubuntu 仓库通常由 Ubuntu 开发人员提供，
so the Ubuntu repositories, for example, are usually provided by the Ubuntu developers,
但是在 Arch Linux 中，可能会有一个叫做 Arch 用户仓库的地方，
but in Arch Linux, there might be something called the Arch User Repository
用户可以自己共享他们自己的库和软件包。
where users can just share their own libraries and their own packages themselves.
仓库往往要么是受管理的，要么完全开放的，
Very often, repositories are either sort of managed or they are just entirely open,
你应该经常意识到这一点，因为如果你使用完全开放的仓库，
and you should often be aware of this because if you're using an entirely open repository,
你从中得到的安全保证可能会比从受控制的仓库中得到的少。
maybe the security guarantees you get from that are less than what you get in a controlled repository.
如果你开始使用仓库，你会注意到一个问题，那就是很多软件都有版本号。
One thing you'll notice if you start using repositories is that very often software is versioned.
我所说的版本，你可能已经在像浏览器这样的东西中看到过了，对吧？
And what I mean by version, well, you might have seen this for stuff like browsers, right?
其中可能有一些像
Where there might be something like
Chrome 版本 64.0.2019.0324 这样的东西，
starting like Chrome version 64.0.2019o324, right?
这是一个版本号。
This is a version number.
它可能有一个点，这是一种版本号。
It might, there's a dot here, this is one kind of version number.
但有时候，如果你开始使用 Photoshop
But sometimes, if you start, I don't know, like Photoshop,
或其他工具，可能会有其他种类的版本号，比如 8.1.7，
or you start any other tool, there might be other kinds of versions that are, like, 8.1.7, right?
这些版本号通常是数字的，但并不总是这样。
These version numbers are usually numerical,  but not always.
有时候它们会在其中添加哈希值，例如为了引用 Git 提交。
Sometimes they have hashes in them, for example, to refer to Git commits.
你可能会问，为什么我们需要这些版本号？
But you might wonder, why do we have these?
为什么在发布软件时添加版本号如此重要呢？
Why is it even important that you add a number to software that you release?
主要原因是它让我们能够知道
The primary reason for this is because it enables me
软件是否会出现故障。
to know whether my software would break.
想象一下，我依赖于Jose编写的一个库，
Imagine that I have a dependency on a library that Jose has written, right?
而Jose一直在对他的库进行更改以使它更好。
And Jose is constantly doing changes to his library because he wants to make it better.
他发现库中公开的一个函数的名称很烂，
And he decides that one of the functions that his library exposes has a bad name,
他决定更改。
so he renames it.
我的软件突然停止工作，
My software suddenly stops working, right?
因为我的库调用了Jose库中的一个函数，
Because my library calls a function on Jose's library,
但是该函数不再存在。
but that function no longer exists.
取决于人们安装的Jose库的版本，
Depending on which version people have installed of Jose's library,
版本号有助于我指定我依赖于Jose库的哪个版本，
version helps solve this because I can say I depend on this version of Jose's library,
并且必须有一些规则来规定在给定版本中Jose可以做什么。
and there have to be some rules around what is Jose allowed to do within a given version.
如果他做了一个我不能再依赖的更改，他的版本必须以某种方式更改。
If he makes a change that I can no longer rely on, his version has to change in some way.
关于这是如何工作的存在许多想法，例如
There are many thoughts on exactly how this should work,
关于版本发布的规则，
like what are the rules for publishing new versions,
版本号如何更改
how do they change the version numbers.
其中一些仅受时间约束。
Some of them are just dictated by time.
例如，如果您看一下浏览器，它们通常具有类似于时间版本的版本号。
So for example, if you look at browsers, they very often have time versions that look like this.
它们在最左侧有一个版本号，表示哪个发布版，
They have a version number on the far left that's just like which release,
然后有一个通常为零的增量号，
and then they have sort of an incremental number that is usually zero,
最后有一个日期。
and then they have a date at the end, right?
因此，这是2019年3月24日的某个版本
So this is March 24th, 2019, for some reason.
通常这，可以从这些信息中得知，这是第64个版本的Firefox。
And usually, that will indicate that this is version 64 of Firefox from this date.
如果他们发布针对安全漏洞的补丁或热修复，
And then, if they release sort of patches or hot fixes for security bugs,
他们可能会增加日期但保持左侧版本不变。
they might increment the date but keep the version of the left the same.
人们对方案的具体内容有着强烈的意见，
And people have strong, strong opinions on exactly what the scheme should be,
而你需要了解其他人使用的方案。
and you sort of depend on knowing what schemes other people use, right?
如果我不知道Jose用于更改版本的方案，
If I don't know what scheme Jose is using for changing his versions,
也许我只能说，你必须运行Jose软件的817版本，
maybe I just have to say, you have to run like 817 of Jose's software,
否则我无法构建我的软件。
otherwise, I cannot build my software.
但这也是一个问题。
But this is a problem, too, right?
想象一下，Jose作为他的库的负责开发人员，
Imagine that Jose, as a responsible developer of his library,
他发现安全漏洞并修复了它，
and he finds the security bug and he fixes it,
但它没有改变库的外部接口。
but it doesn't change the external interfaces library.
没有函数改变，没有类型改变。
No functions change, no types change.
然后我希望人们使用他的新版本来构建我的软件，
Then I want people to be building my software with his new version,
恰好构建我的软件可以使用他的新版本，
and it just so happens that building mine works just fine with his new version
因为那个特定版本没有改变我所依赖的任何东西。
because that particular version didn't change anything I depended on.
因此，对此的一种尝试解决方案是称为语义版本控制。
So one attempted solution to this is something called semantic versioning.
在语义版本控制中，我们为版本号中
In semantic versioning, we give each of the numbers
由点分隔的每个数字赋予特定的含义，
separated by dots in a version number a particular meaning.
并为不同数字的增加制定合同。
And we give a contract for when you have to increment the different numbers.
特别是在语义化版本控制中，我们称这个为主要版本，这个为次要版本，
In particular, in semantic versioning, we call this the major version, we call this the minor version,
这个为补丁版本。
and we call this the patch version.
其规则如下：
The rules around this are as follows:
如果你对你的软件进行了完全向后兼容的更改，
if you make a change to your software
例如不添加任何东西，
and the change you made is entirely backwards compatible,
不删除任何东西，不在外部重命名任何东西，就像什么也没有改变一样，
like it does not add anything, it does not remove anything, it does not rename anything
那么你只增加补丁号，不做其他更改。
externally, it is as if nothing changed, then you only increment the patch number, nothing else.
通常，例如安全修复会增加补丁号。
Usually, security fixes, for example, will increment the patch number.
如果你添加了库中的某些内容
If you add something to your library
（我只是称其为库，因为通常库是这种情况下需要考虑的内容），
(I'm just gonna call them libraries because usually libraries are the things where this matters),
所以对于库，如果你添加了一些东西
So to library, if you add some thing to library
则增加次要版本并将补丁设置为零。
you increment the minor version and you set the patch to zero.
在这种情况下，如果我们要进行一个次要发布，
In this case, if we were to do a minor release,
则下一个次要发布版本号将为 8-0。
the next minor release version number would be eight to zero.
我们这样做的原因是，
And the reason we do this is because
我可能对 José 在 2.0 中添加的某个特性有依赖性，
I might have a dependency on a feature that José added in a 2-0,
这意味着你不能使用 8-1-7 构建我的软件。
which means you can't build my software with 8-1-7.
这可能不太行，尽管...
That would not be okay, even though
如果你已经将其编写为 8-1-7，你可以在 2-0 上运行它。
if you had written it towards 8-1-7, you could run it with a 2-0.
反之则不是这样，因为它可能尚未添加。
The reverse is not true because it might not have been added yet.
最后，如果进行了向后不兼容的更改，则增加主要版本。
And then, finally, the major version you increment if you make a backwards incompatible change.
如果我的软件以前可以使用你所拥有的任何版本，
Where if my software used to work with whatever version you had,
然后你做出了一些改变，这意味着我的软件可能不再工作，
and then you make a change that means that my software might no longer work,
例如删除或重命名函数，
such as removing a function or renaming it,
则增加主要版本并将次要和补丁设置为零。
then you increment the major version and set minor and patch to zero.
因此，下一个主要版本将是 9-0-0。
So, the next major version here would be 9-0-0.
综合在一起，这些使我们能够在设置我们的依赖项时做很好的事情。
Taken together, these allow us to do really nice things when setting what our dependencies are.
特别是，如果我依赖于某个人的库的特定版本，
In particular, if I depend on a particular version of someone's library,
而不是说它必须完全是这个版本，
rather than saying it has to be exactly this version,
我真正想表达的是它必须是相同的主要版本，
what I'm really saying is it has to be the same major version
至少是相同的次要版本，
and at least the same minor version,
并且补丁可以是任何内容。
and the patch can be whatever.
这意味着，如果我依赖于 José 的软件，
This means that if I have a dependency on José's software,
则仍在同一主要版本内的任何后续版本都可以。
then any later release that is still within the same major is fine.
请记住，这包括较早的版本，假设次要版本相同。
That includes, keep in mind, an earlier version, assuming that the minor is the same.
想象一下，你在某台装有 8.1.3 版本的旧计算机上。
Imagine that you are on some older computer that has version 8.1.3.
理论上，我的软件也应该可以正常工作在 8.1.3 版本上。
In theory, my software should work just fine with 8.1.3 as well.
它可能有 José 在其中修复的任何漏洞，例如任何安全问题。
It might have whatever bug that José fixed in between, like whatever security issue.
但这具有很好的特性，现在你可以
But this has the nice property that now you can share dependencies
在计算机上的许多不同软件之间共享依赖关系。
between many different pieces of software on your machine.
如果您已经安装了8.3.0版本，
If you have version 8.3.0 installed
并且有许多不同的软件需要8.1.7、8.2.4
and there are bunch of different software that one requires 8.1.7, one requires 8.2.4,
和8.0.1版本中的一个，那么它们都可以使用同一个依赖版本。
and one requires 8.0.1, all of them can use the same version of that dependency.
您只需要安装一次即可。
You only need to install it once.
这种语义化版本控制中最常见或最熟悉的例子之一
One of the most common or most familiar, perhaps,
是Python版本控制。
examples of this kind of semantic versioning is if you look at the Python versioning.
你们中的许多人可能已经遇到过这个问题，
Many of you may have come across this,
Python 3和Python 2彼此不兼容。
where Python 3 and Python 2 are not compatible with one another.
它们不向后兼容。
They're not backwards compatible.
如果你在Python 2中编写代码并尝试在Python 3中运行它，它可能不起作用。
If you write code in Python 2 and try to run it in Python 3, it might not work.
有些情况下会起作用，
There are some cases where it will,
但那更多的是偶然而非其他。
but that is more accidental than anything else.
Python实际上遵循语义化版本控制，至少大部分是这样。
Python actually follows semantic versioning, at least mostly.
如果你编写运行在Python 3.5上的软件，那么它也应该在3.6、3.7和3.8上运行。
If you write software that runs on Python 3.5, then it should also work in 3.6, 3.7,  and 3.8.
它不一定会在Python 4上运行，虽然那可能还需要很长一段时间。
It will not necessarily work in Python 4, although that will hopefully be a long time away.
但如果你为Python 3.5编写代码，它可能不会在Python 3.4上运行。
But if you write code for Python 3.5, it will possibly not run on Python 3.4.
因此，你会看到许多软件项目
So, one thing you will see many software projects do is
尽可能降低它们的版本要求。
they try to bring the version requirements they have as low as possible.
如果你可以依赖主版本和次版本以及修补版本0.0，
If you can depend on major and then minor in patch 0.0,
那么这是你可以拥有的最好的依赖关系，
that is the best possible dependency
因为它完全自由地依赖于你正在依赖的主要版本的哪个版本。
you can have because it is completely liberal as to which version of that major you're depending on.
有时这很难。
Sometimes this is hard.
有时你确实需要添加一个特性，
Sometimes you genuinely need a feature that was added,
但你可以把版本要求降到最低，这对于那些想要依赖你的软件的人来说是最好的。
but the lower you can get, the better it is for those who want to depend on your software in turn
反过来，在处理这些依赖管理系统或一般版本控制时，
when working with these sort of dependency management systems or in with versioning in general,
你经常会遇到锁定文件的概念。
you'll often come across this notion of lock files.
你可能已经看到过这个问题，当你尝试做某事时，
You might have seen this where you try to do something
它会说“无法协调版本”，
and it says, "Cannot reconcile versions"
或者你会收到像“锁定文件已经存在”这样的错误。
or you get an error like, "Lock file already exists."
这些通常是有些不同的主题，
These are often somewhat different topics,
但总的来说，锁定文件的概念是为了
but in general, the notion of a lock file is to make sure that
确保你不会意外地更新某些东西。
you don't accidentally update something.
锁定文件本质上只是一个列出你依赖关系
The lock file, at its core, is really just a list of your dependencies
及其当前使用版本的列表。
and which version of them you are currently using.
我的版本字符串可能是8.1.7，
My version string might be 8.1.7,
而最新版本可能是3.0，
and the latest version, like on the internet somewhere, might be 3.0,
但在我的系统上安装的版本不一定是其中的一个。
but whatever is installed on my system is not necessarily one of those two.
它可能是8.2.4或类似的版本，
It might be like 8.2.4 or something like that,
锁定文件会说“依赖José的8.2.4版本”。
and the lock file will then say, "Dependency José version 8.2.4."
你想要一个锁定文件的原因有很多。
The reason you want a lock file, there can be many.
其中一个原因是您可能希望构建速度快。
One of them is that you might want your builds to be fast.
如果每次尝试构建项目时，
if every single time you try to build your project,
您使用的任何工具都会下载最新版本，
whatever tool you were using download the latest version
然后编译它，再编译您的项目，
and then compile it and then compile your thing,
那么每次等待时间可能会很长，
you might wait for a really long time each time,
具体取决于依赖项的发布周期。
depending on the release cycle of your dependencies.
如果您使用锁文件，
If you use a lock file, then unless the version,
除非您已在锁文件中更新了版本，
unless you've updated the version in your lock file,
否则它将仅使用之前为该依赖项构建的内容，
it'll just use whatever it built previously for that dependency
您的开发周期可以更快。
and your sort of development cycle can be a lot faster.
使用锁文件的另一个原因是为了获得可重复的构建。
Another reason to use lock files is to get reproducible builds.
假设我生产了一些与安全相关的软件，
Imagine that I produce some kind of security-related software,
我非常仔细地审查了我的依赖关系，
and I very carefully audited my dependencies,
并生成了一个签名的二进制文件，
and I produce, like, a signed binary of, like,
例如“这是我的宣誓声明，证明这个版本是安全的”。
'Here is, thus, like a sworn statement for me that this version is secure.'
如果我没有包含锁文件，那么当其他人安装我的程序时，
If I didn't include a lock file, then by the time someone else installs my program,
他们可能会得到一个更晚的依赖版本，
they might get a later version of their pendency,
而这个版本可能已被黑客攻击
and maybe that later version as I've been hacked somehow
或存在其他安全漏洞，
or just has some other security vulnerability
而我还没有机会查看。
that I haven't had a chance to look at yet, right?
锁文件基本上允许我冻结生态系统，因为它是我已检查的版本。
And a lock file basically allows me to freeze the ecosystem as of this version that I have checked.
这种做法的极端版本是一种称为“vendoring”的东西。
The extreme version of this is something called 'vendoring.
当您对依赖项进行vendoring时，实际上就是将它们复制/粘贴到项目中。
When you vendor your dependencies, it really just means you copy/paste of them.
Vendoring意味着将您关心的任何依赖项
Vendoring means take whatever dependency you care about
复制到您的项目中，
and copy it into your project because that way,
因为这样您就完全确定了将获得该依赖项的版本。
you are entirely sure that you will get that version of that dependency.
这也意味着您可以自己修改它，
It also means that you can, like, make modifications to it on your own,
但它的缺点是您将不再获得版本控制的好处。
but it has the downsides that now you no longer get these benefits of versioning, right?
当一个新的发行版出现时，
You no longer have the advantage that if there are newer releases of that software,
您将无法自动获取软件的新版本，
your users might get them automatically, like,
例如当Hosea修复其安全问题时（当然他没有安全问题）。
for example, when Hosea fixes his security issues, not that he has any of course.
您会注意到，当谈论这个问题时，我一直在谈论系统中的一些更大的过程。
One thing you'll notice is that when talking about this,
我已经说了很多关于系统的大的过程
I've been talking about sort of bigger processes around your systems.
这些过程包括测试，
These are things like testing.
检查依赖关系版本
They're things like checking your dependency versions.
以及设置构建系统等。
They're also things that are just setting up build systems,
通常，您不只想要一个本地构建系统，
and often you don't just want a local build system.
您希望构建过程包括其他类型的系统，
You want to build process that includes other types of systems,
即使您的计算机不一定开着，它们也可以运行。，
or you want them to run even when your computer is not necessarily on,
因此，随着您开始处理越来越大的项目，
and this is why, as you start working a larger and larger project,
您会看到人们使用持续集成的概念，
you will see people use this idea of continuous integration,
持续集成系统本质上是一个云构建系统。
and continuous integration systems are essentially a cloud build system.
这意味着您的项目存储在互联网的某个地方，
The idea is that you have your project stored on the internet somewhere,
并且您已经使用某种服务
and you have set it up with some kind of service
为您的项目运行持续集成，无论它是什么。
that is running an ongoing thing for your project, whatever it might be,
持续集成可以是各种各样的东西。
and continuous integration can be all sorts of stuff.
它可以是像将您的库自动发布到PyPI一样简单，
It can be stuff like releasing your library to PyPI automatically
每次提交到特定分支时。
whenever you push to a particular branch.
它可以是类似于每当有人提交拉取请求时运行测试套件，
It could be things like run your test suite  whenever someone submits a pull request,
或者可以是每次提交代码时检查您的代码风格。
or it could be check your code style every time you commit.
您可以通过持续集成实现各种各样的事情，
There all sorts of things you could do with continuous integration,
最简单的方法是将它们视为事件触发的操作。
and the easiest way to think about them is that they're sort of event-triggered actions.
因此，每当某个事件发生时，可能会针对您的项目发生特定的操作，
So, whenever a particular event happens for your, possibly for your project,
其中操作通常是某种脚本、一系列要调用的程序，
a particular action takes place, where the action is usually some kind of script,
它们将执行某些操作。
some sequence of programs that are going to be invoked,  and they're going to do something.
这实际上是一个涵盖了许多不同类型的服务的大伞术语。
This is really an umbrella term that encapsulates a lot of different types of services.
一些持续集成服务是非常通用的东西，比如Travis CI、Azure pipelines
Some continuous integration services are very general things like Travis CI or Azure pipelines,
或GitHub actions都是非常广泛的CI平台。
or GitHub actions are all very broad CI platforms.
它们旨在让您编写
They're built to let you write what you want to happen
在您定义的任何事件发生时要发生的操作，非常广泛的系统。
whenever any event that you define happens, very broad systems.
还有一些更专业的系统，处理诸如持续集成覆盖测试之类的事情。
There are some more specialized systems that deal with things like continuous integration coverage testing.
所以，像注释你的代码并展示你没有测试这段代码，
So, like annotate your code and show you have no tests that test this piece of code,
它们仅用于这个目的，
and they're built only for that purpose,
或者它们仅用于测试基于浏览器的库之类的东西。
or they're built only for testing browser-based libraries or something like that.
因此，通常你可以找到为你正在工作的特定项目构建的CI工具，
And so, often you can find CI tools that are built for the particular project you're working on,
或者你可以使用其中的一个更广泛的提供者。
or you can use one of these broader providers.
而且，其中一个好处是，许多CI工具实际上是免费的，特别是针对开源软件，
And one thing that's nice is that many of them are actually free,  especially for open source software,
或者如果你是学生，你也经常可以免费获得它们。
or if you're a student,  you can often get them for free as well.
一般来说，你使用CI系统的方式是向你的代码库添加一个文件，
In general, the way you use the CI system is that you add a file to your repository,
这个文件通常称为“recipe”。
and this file is often known as a recipe.
而这个recipe指定的内容是这种依赖循环，
And what the recipe specifies is this sort of dependency cycle again,
就像我们在make文件中看到的那样，但并不完全相同。
sort of what we saw with make files, it's not quite the same.
事件，而不是文件，可能是这样的，比如当有人推送提交时，
The events, instead of being files, might be something like when someone pushes a commit
当提交包含特定的消息时，
or when a commit contains a particular message
或者当有人提交pull request或持续写入时。
or when someone submits a pull request or continuously write.
一个不与你的代码的任何特定更改相关的
One example of a continuous integration service
持续集成服务的例子是Dependabot。
that's not tied to any particular change to your code is something called the Dependabot.
你可以在GitHub上找到它，
You can find this on GitHub,
而Dependabot是你连接到你的代码库中的一个东西，
and the Dependabot is something that you hook up to your repository,
它将只扫描你没有使用的依赖项中是否有更新的版本。
and it will just scan whether there are newer versions available of your dependencies that you're not using.
因此，例如，如果我依赖于8.1.7，并且我有一个锁定文件将它锁定在8.2.4上，
So, for example, if I was depending on 8.1.7 and I had a lock file that locked it to 8.2.4,
然后8.3.0发布了，Dependabot会说：
and then 8.3.0 is released, the Dependabot will go,
“你应该更新你的锁定文件”，
"You should update your lock file,"
然后向你的代码库提交该更新的pull request。
and then submit the pull request to your repository with that update.
这是一个持续集成服务。
This is a continuous integration service.
它不是与我改变任何东西相关，而是与生态系统的整体变化相关。
It's not tied to me changing anything but to the ecosystem at large changing.
这些CI系统通常也会与你的项目集成。
Often these CI systems integrate back into your project as well.
因此，这些CI服务经常会提供一些小徽章之类的东西。
So, very often, these CI services will provide things like little badges.
让我举个例子。
Let me give an example.
例如，这是我最近参与的一个设置了持续集成的项目。
So, for example, here's a project I've worked on recently that has continuous integration set up.
所以，这个项目，你会注意到它的README。
So, this project, you'll notice it's README.
如果我可以用那个Chrome bean放大它，不，不，那比我想要的大得多。
If I can zoom in here with that Chrome bean, nope, nope, that's much larger than I wanted.
在这里，你会看到在代码库页面的顶部有一堆这样的徽章，
Here, you'll see that at the top of the repositories page, there are a bunch of these badges,
它们显示各种类型的信息。
and they display various types of information.
你会注意到我正在运行Dependable，对吧？
You'll notice that I have dependable running, right?
所以依赖项当前是最新的。
So the dependencies are currently up to date.
它告诉我主分支上的测试套件是否正在通过。
It tells me about whether the test suite is currently passing on the master branch.
它告诉我代码中有多少被测试覆盖了，
It tells me how much of the code is covered by tests,
并告诉我这个库的最新版本
and it tells me what is the latest version of this library
和在线可用的文档版本。
and what is the latest version of the documentation of the library that's available online.
所有这些都由各种持续集成服务管理。
And all of these are managed by various continuous integration services.
另一个你们中有些人可能会发现有用甚至熟悉的例子
Another example that some of you might find useful or might even be familiar with is
是GitHub Pages。
the notion of GitHub Pages.
GitHub Pages是GitHub提供的一个非常好的服务，
So GitHub Pages is a really nice service the GitHub provides
它允许你设置一个CI操作，将你的存储库构建为博客。
which lets you set up a CI action that builds your repository as a blog essentially.
它运行一个静态站点生成器称为Jekyll，
It runs a static site generator called Jekyll,
Jekyll只需要一堆Markdown文件，然后生成一个完整的网站。
and Jekyll just takes a bunch of markdown files and then produces a complete website.
作为GitHub Pages的一部分，它们还会将其上传到GitHub服务器
And that, as a part of GitHub Pages, they will also upload that to GitHub servers
并在特定域名下提供。
and make it available at a particular domain.
这实际上是课堂网站的工作方式。
And this is actually how the class website works.
课堂网站不是一堆我们管理的HTML页面。
The class website is not a bunch of like HTML pages that we manage.
相反，有一个名为'Missing Semester'的存储库。
Instead, there's a repository 'Missing Semester.'
如果你查看Missing Semester存储库，你会看到，
So if you look at the Missing Semester repository, you will see,
如果我在这里缩小一下，它只有一堆Markdown文件。
if I zoom out a little here, that this just has a bunch of markdown files.
这里有'Saket 20/20 - Metaprogramming.md'，
Right? It has 'Saket 20/20 - Metaprogramming.md,'
所以这是今天讲座的原始Markdown。
so this is the raw markdown for today's lecture.
这是我编写讲座笔记的方式，
So this is the way that I write the lecture notes,
然后我将其提交到我们的存储库，并将其推送。
and then I commit that to the repository we have,  and I push it.
每当发生推送时，
And whenever a push happens,
GitHub Pages CI将运行GitHub Pages的构建脚本，
the GitHub Pages CI is gonna run the build script for GitHub Pages
并为我们的课程生成网站，
and produces the website for our class
而无需我执行任何其他步骤来完成这一过程。
without me having to do any additional steps to make that happen.
所以，是的。
And so, yeah,
所以Jekyll，它使用一个称为Jekyll的工具，
So Jekyll, it's using a tool called Jekyll, which is a tool that
它是一个将包含Markdown文件的目录结构转换成网站的工具。
takes a directory structure that contains markdown files and produces a website.
它会生成像HTML文件这样的文件，
It produces like HTML files,
然后作为操作的一部分，
and then as a part of the action,
它会将这些文件上传到GitHub服务器的一个特定域名下，
it takes those files and uploads them to GitHub servers at a particular domain,
通常是他们控制的'github.io'域名下。
and usually, that's the domain under like 'github.io' that they control.
然后我将Missing Semester设置为指向GitHub域名。
And then I have set Missing Semester to point to the GitHub domain.
我想给大家一个关于测试的旁白，
I want to give you one aside on testing
因为这是你们中很多人以前可能熟悉的东西，
because it's something that many of you may be familiar with from before, right?
对测试有一个大致的概念。
You have a rough idea of what testing is.
你会在之前运行测试。
You run the test before.
你曾经看过测试失败。
You've seen a test fail.
你知道基础知识，或者你从来没有见过测试失败。
You know, like the basics of it, or maybe you've never seen a test fail.
如果你已经掌握了这些知识，那么恭喜你，
In case congratulations,
但是当你开始涉及更高级的项目时，
but as you get to more advanced projects, though,
你会发现人们对于测试有很多专业术语。
you'll find that people have a lot of terminology around testing.
测试是一个非常深入的主题，
and testing is a pretty deep subject
你可能需要花费许多时间来理解其中的细节。
that you could spend many many hours trying to understand the ins and outs of,
虽然我不会详细介绍所有的内容，
and I'm not going to go through it in excruciating detail,
但是有几个词汇我认为是有用的，你需要知道它们的含义。
but there are a couple of words that I think it's useful to know what mean.
第一个是测试套件。
And the first of these is a test suite.
测试套件是程序中所有测试的简单名称。
So a test suite is a very straightforward name for all of the tests in a program.
它只是一组测试，通常作为一个整体运行，
It's really just a suite of tests, it's a large collection of tests that usually are run as a unit,
通常由不同类型的测试组成。
and there are different types of tests that often make up a test suite.
第一个类型是单元测试。
The first of these is what's known as a unit test.
单元测试是一种通常比较小的、自包含的测试，用于测试一个单一的功能。
A unit test is a, often usually fairly small, test of self-contained tests that tests a single feature.
什么是一个功能可能有点取决于项目，
What exactly a feature might mean is a little bit up to the project,
但是这个想法是应该有一个微型测试，只测试一个非常特定的东西。
but the idea is that should be sort of a micro test that only tests a very particular thing.
然后你有更大的测试，称为集成测试。
Then you have the larger tests that are known as integration tests.
集成测试尝试测试程序的不同子系统之间的交互。
Integration tests try to test the interaction between different subsystems of a program.
所以这可能是这样一个例子：
So this might be something like, an example of a unit test might be
如果你正在编写一个 HTML 解析器，单元测试可能是测试它是否能够解析 HTML 标记。
if you're writing an HTML parser, the unit test might be test that it can parse an HTML tag.
而集成测试可能是这样一个例子：这是一个 HTML 文档，请解析它。
An integration test might be, here's an HTML document, parse it.
这将是解析器的多个子系统的集成。
So that is going to be the integration of multiple of the subsystems of the parser.
你还有一个称为回归测试的概念。
You also have a notion of regression tests.
回归测试是测试过去出现过问题的东西。
Regression tests are tests that test things that were broken in the past.
假设有人向你提交了一个问题，
So imagine that someone submits some kind of issue to you
并说如果我给它一个跑马灯标记，
and says your library breaks if I give it a marquee tag,
你的库就会出现问题，这让你很难过，所以你想要修复它。
and that makes you sad,  so you want to fix it.
因此，你将修复解析器以支持我的标记，
So you fix your parser to now support my key tags,
并在测试套件中添加一个检查是否可以解析跑马灯标记的测试。
but then you want to add a test to your test suite that checks that you can parse marquee tags.
这样做的原因是为了
The reason for this is so that in the future,
将来不会再次引入该错误。
you don't accidentally reintroduce that bug.
因此，回归测试非常有用，
So that is what regression tests are for,
随着时间的推移，你的项目将会积累越来越多这样的测试，
and over time your project is gonna build up more and more of these,
它们非常好，因为它们可以防止项目退回到早期的 bug。
and they're nice because they prevent your project from regressing to earlier bugs.
我想要提及的最后一个概念是模拟。
The last one I want to mention is a concept called mocking.
"mocking"是指能够用一种虚拟的方式替换掉系统的某些部分，
So mocking is the idea of being able to replace parts of your system
这种虚拟版本的行为是由你控制的。
with a sort of dummy version of itself that behaves in a way that you control.
一个常见的例子是，你正在编写一个
A common example of this is you're writing something that does, oh I don't know,
emm..用ssh拷贝文件？
file copying over SSH.
是的，通过SSH进行文件拷贝的工具。
Right? This is a tool that you've written that does file copying over SSH.
在这里，你可能想要模拟许多东西。
There are many things you might want to mock here.
例如，在运行测试套件时，
For example, when running your test suite, you probably don't actually care that there's a network there.
你可能并不关心是否有网络存在。
Right? You don't need to have to like set up TCP ports and stuff,
所以，你可以模拟网络。
so instead you're gonna mock the network.
通常的做法是，在你的库中，
The way this usually works is that, somewhere in your library,
有一些东西打开连接，从连接中读取数据，或者向连接中写入数据。
you have something that like opens a connection, or reads from the connection, or writes to the connection,
你会在你的库内部覆盖这些函数，
and you're gonna overwrite those functions internally in your library
使用你专门为测试而编写的函数。
with functions that you've written just for the purposes of testing,
例如，读取函数只会返回数据，
where the read function just like returns the data,
写入函数只会将数据丢弃。
and the write function just drops the data on the floor, or something like that.
同样，你可以为SSH功能编写一个模拟函数。
Similarly, you can write a mocking function for the SSH functionality.
你可以编写一个不实际进行加密和与网络通信的函数。
You could write something that does not actually do encryption,
这跟网络无关
it doesn't talk to the network:
这个函数只是接收字节，然后在另一端神奇地将它们弹出来。
it just like takes bytes in here and just magically they pop out the other side,
你可以忽略其中的一切，
and you can ignore everything that's between,
因为对于文件拷贝的目的，如果你只是想测试该功能，
because for the purpose of copying a file, if you just wanted to test that functionality,
那么下面的内容对于该测试并不重要。
the stuff below doesn't matter for that test,
你可能会嘲笑它。
and you might mock it away.
通常情况下，在任何一种语言中，都有工具可以很容易地构建这些模拟抽象。
Usually, in any given language, there are tools that let you build these kind of mocking abstractions pretty easily.
这就是我想讨论元编程的全部内容，
That is the end of what I wanted to talk about metaprogramming,
但这是一个非常广泛的主题。
but this is a very, very broad subject.
像持续集成、构建系统这样的东西，
Things like continuous integration, build systems,
有很多可以让你对你的项目做很多有趣的事情，
there are so many out there that can let you do so many interesting things with your projects,
所以我强烈建议你稍微了解一下。
so I highly recommend that you start looking into it a little.
这些练习内容比较散，
The exercises are sort of all over the place,
但这是件好事。
and I mean that in a good way.
它们旨在尝试向你展示构建
They're intended to try to just show you the kind of possibilities that exist
和处理这些过程的各种可能性。
for building and working with these kind of processes.
例如，最后一个练习让你自己编写一个持续集成操作，
So, for example, the last exercise has you write one of these continuous integration actions yourself
你可以决定事件和操作是什么，
where you decide what the event be and you decide what the action be,
但要尝试真正地构建一个。
but try to actually build one.
这可能是你在项目中会发现有用的东西。
And this can be something that you might find useful in your project.
我在练习中给出的示例是
The example I gave in the exercises is
尝试构建一个操作，对你的存储库运行英语语言的语法检查，例如RightGood或Proselint。
to try to build an action that runs like write good or
如果你真的这样做了，我们可以在课堂存储库中启用它，
And if you do like, we could enable that for the class repository
这样我们的讲义就会写得很好。
so that our lecture notes are actually well written. Right？
这种持续集成测试的另一个好处是，
and this is one other thing that's nice about this kind of continuous integration testing,
你可以在项目之间进行协作。
is that you can collaborate between projects.
如果你编写了一个，我可以在我的项目中使用它，
If you write one, I can use it in my project,
and there's a really handy feature where you can build this ecosystem of improving everything.
今天录制的任何内容有任何问题吗？是的，
Any questions about any of the stuff we recorded today? Yeah,
问题是，为什么我们既有make又有CMake？它们都是做什么的？
so the question is, why do we have both make and CMake? What do they do,
它们之间有交流的原因吗？
and is there a reason for them to talk together?
所以，CMake，我实际上不知道CMake的标语是什么，
So, CMake, I don't actually know what the tagline for CMake is anymore,
但它有点像C语言的更好的make。
but it's sort of like a better make for C.
顾名思义，
As the name implies, CMake generally
CMake通常比make文件更好地了解C项目的布局。
understands the layout of C projects a little bit better than make files do.
它们的建立是为了尝试解析您的依赖项结构是什么，
They're sort of built to try to parse out what the structure of your dependencies are,
从一个规则到另一个规则的转换。
what the rules are from going to one to the other.
它还与像系统库这样的东西集成得更好，
It also integrates a little bit nicer with things like system libraries,
因此CMake可以执行诸如检测计算机上的给定库是否可用，
so CMake can do things like detect given libraries available on your computer
或者如果该库在多个不同的路径上可用，
or if it's available at multiple different paths,
它会尝试找到其所在的路径，然后进行适当的链接。
it tries to find which of those paths it's present on on this system and then link it appropriately.
因此，CMake比make更智能。
So CMake is a little bit smarter than make.
make将只执行您在make文件中放置的任何内容。
Make will only do whatever you put in the make file.
这不是完全正确的，有称为隐式规则的东西，它们是make中的内置规则，
Not entirely true, there are things called implicit rules that are like built-in rules in make,
但它们非常简单，而CMake则尝试成为一个大型构建系统，
but they're pretty dumb, whereas CMake tries to be able to be a larger build system that is
它默认针对C项目工作。
opinionated by default to work for C projects.
同样，还有一个名为Maven和Ant的工具，这是另一个项目。
Similarly, there's a tool called Maven and Ant, which is another project.
它们都是为Java项目构建的。
They are both built for Java projects.
它们了解Java代码如何相互交互，如何构造Java程序，
They understand how Java code interacts with one another, how you structure Java programs,
并为此而构建。
and they're built for that task.
通常，当我使用make时，
Very often, at least when I use make,
我会在顶部使用make，然后使其他工具
I use make sort of at the top and then make my call other tools that build
构建的任何你知道的子系统。
whatever subsystem they know how to build.
right,like my make file,
and then call cmake to build like c dependency of that
I'm gonna do some stuff at the end of
对我来说，make是我可能编写的顶部粘合剂。
For me, make is sort of the glue at the top that I might write.
通常，如果您的make文件变得非常大，有更好的工具。
Usually, if your make file gets very large, there's a better tool.
您会发现在大公司，例如谷歌，
What you'll find at big companies, for example,
他们通常有一个构建系统来管理其所有软件。
is they often have one build system that manages all of their software.
因此，如果您看看谷歌，他们有这个名为Basil的开源系统，
So if you look at Google, for example, they have this open-source system called Basil,
我不认为谷歌在谷歌内部直接使用Basil，
and I don't think Google literally uses Basil inside of Google,
但它基于他们在内部使用的构建系统。
but it's sort of based on what they use internally.
And it's really just intended to manage the entire build of everything Google has.
Basil实际上是建立为一种多语言构建框架，
And Basil, in particular, is built to be, I think they call it, like a polyglot build framework.
因此，这个想法适用于许多不同的语言。
So the idea is that it works for many different languages.
有像这种语言和那种语言的Basil模块，
There's like an implement, there's a module for Basil for this language and that language in that language,
但它们都与相同的Basil框架集成，
but they all integrate with the same Basil framework,
然后该框架知道如何在不同库和不同语言之间集成依赖项。
which then knows how to integrate dependencies between different libraries and different languages.
你有问题吗？
Got a question? Sure.
当你说表达式时，你是指这个文件中的东西吗？
So when you say expressions, you mean the things in this file? Or yeah,
是的，
so these are ...
所以make文件是它们自己的语言。
so make files are their own language
这是一种相当奇怪的语言。
They are...It's a pretty weird language.
就像Bash一样，它有很多奇怪的例外。
Like, it has a lot of weird exceptions.
在很多方面，它就像Bash一样奇怪，
In many ways, it's weird just like bash is weird,
但在不同的方面更糟糕。
but in different ways, which is even worse.
当你编写makefile时，
Like, when you're writing a make file, you sort of,
你可能会认为自己正在编写Bash，
you can sort of think like you're writing bash,
但实际上它有不同的错误。
but you're not because it's broken in different ways.
但是，它确实是一种独立的语言。
but it is its own language.
makefile通常的结构是你有一系列的指令，
And the way that make files are generally structured
我想他们称之为指令。
is that you have a sequence of, I think they call them directives.
所以，每一个喜欢，这个东西（哎呀）这个东西是一个指令，
So, every like, this thing (oops) this thing is a directive,
这是一个指令。
and this is a directive.
每个指令都有一个冒号，
And every directive has a colon somewhere,
在冒号左侧的是一个目标，
and everything to the left of the colon is a target,
在冒号右侧的是一个依赖项。
and everything to the right of the colon is right of the colon is a dependency.
然后，下面的所有行都是操作序列，
And then all of the lines below that line
也称为规则，用于一旦你有了依赖项，
are the sequence of operations known as the rules for once you have the dependencies.
如何构建这些目标？
How do you build these targets?
注意，makefile非常注重你必须使用制表符来缩进规则。
Notice that make is very particular that you must use a tab to indent the rules.
如果不这样做，make就不会工作。
If you do not, make will not work.
它们必须是制表符，不能是4或8个空格，
If they must be tabs, they cannot be four eight spaces.
必须是制表符。
Must be tabs.
你可以在这里有多个操作。
And like, you can have multiple operations here.
我可以做echo hello或其他什么，
I like I can do echo hello or whatever,
然后它们将首先运行这个，然后运行这个。
and then they would first run this and then run this.
今天的讲座中有一个练习，
There's a there's an exercise for today's lecture that
让你尝试扩展这个makefile，加入一些其他有趣的目标，
has you try to extend this make file with a couple of other targets that
更详细地介绍一下。
you might find interesting that goes into a little bit more detail.
还有一些能力来执行外部命令，
There's also some ability to execute external commands
以确定依赖项可能是什么，
to like determine what the dependencies might be
如果你的依赖项不是静态文件列表，
if your dependencies are not like a static list of files,
但是它有一点限制。
but it's a little limited.
通常，一旦你开始需要这种东西，
Usually, once you've started needing that sort of stuff,
你可能需要转移到更高级的构建系统。
you might want to move to a more advanced build system.
是的，
Yeah,
问题是，如果我有，假设我有库a和库b，
so the question is what happens if I have, let's say that I have library a and library b,
它们都依赖于库c，
and they both depend on library c,
但库a依赖于4.0.1，
but library a depends on like 4.0.1,
库b依赖于3.4.7，
and library b depends on 3.4.7.
所以它们都依赖于 c，
So they both depend on c,
理想情况下，我们希望重用 c，
and so ideally, we'd like to reuse c,
但它们依赖于不同的主要版本的 c。
but they depend on different major versions of c.
我们该怎么办？
What do we do?
这种情况下发生的情况完全取决于您正在使用的系统和语言。
Well, what happens in this case depends entirely on the system that
呃呃呃
you're using, the language that you're using.
在某些情况下，工具会选择其中一个版本，
In some cases, the tool would just be like, well, I'll just pick for
这暗示它们实际上没有使用语义化版本控制。
which sort of implies that they're not really using semantic versioning.
在某些情况下，工具会显示“不可能”。
In some cases, the tool will say, this is not possible.
如果这样做，会导致错误，
Like, if you do this, it's an error,
并且工具将告诉您需要升级 b，
and the tool will tell you you either need to upgrade b ,
例如使 b 使用 c 的较新版本，或者降级 a。
like have b use a newer version of c, or you need to downgrade a.
你不能这样做，
You do not get to do this,
编译将失败。
and compilation will fail.
有些工具将构建两个版本的 c，
Some tools are gonna build two versions of c,
然后在构建 a 时使用 c 的主要版本 4，
and then like when it builds a, it will use the major four version of c,
在构建 b 时使用 c 的主要版本 3。
and when it builds b, it will use the major three version of c.
你最终会遇到一些非常奇怪的情况，
One thing you end up with is really weird conditions here were like
例如如果 c 有依赖项，
你可能会遇到特别奇怪的情况。
if c has dependencies,
则现在必须将所有 c 的依赖项都构建两次，一次用于 3，一次用于 4，
then now you have to build all of c's dependencies twice to 1 for 3 and 1 for 4,
也许它们共享，也许它们不共享。
and maybe they share and maybe they don't.
最后这将会大寄特寄
You can end up in particularly weird situations.
如果想象一下库 c，
If imagine that the library c, like...
比如说库 c 写入一个文件，比如说写入磁盘上的一些缓存。
imagine that library c  , like rights to a file, like rights to some like file on disk, some cache stuff.
如果现在运行您的应用程序，a 做了一些调用，比如调用 c.save，
If you run your application now and like a does something to call like c. save
而 b 做了一些调用，比如调用 c.adult load，
and b to something like c.adult load,
那么底层的应用程序就不会工作，因为格式是不同的，对吧？
then suddenly your application of the bottom is not going to work because the format is different, right?
因此，这些情况通常非常棘手，
So, these situations are often very problematic,
大多数支持语义化版本控制的工具会因为这个原因拒绝这种配置。
and most tools that support semantic versioning will reject this kind of configuration for exactly that reason.
但是，要自己搞砸是很容易的。
But it's so easy to shoot yourself in the foot.
好了，我们明天再见，进行安全方面的学习。
All right, we will see you again tomorrow for security.
请记住，如果您还没有填写问卷调查，请务必参加。
Keep in mind, again, if you haven't done the survey,
在问卷调查中，我最关心的问题是
the question I care the most about in the survey
您希望我们在最后两节课中涵盖什么内容。
is what you would like us to cover in the last two lectures.
因此，请选择您想要我们讨论的主题
So, the last two lectures are for you to choose what you want us to talk about
并提出任何问题。
and to give any questions you want us to answer.
如果可以，请填写问卷调查。
So please, like, add that if you can.
就这样，
And that's it.
明天见。
See you tomorrow.